<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Analysis on Ankit Dhall</title>
    <link>https://ankit-dhall.github.io/portfolio/tags/data-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Analysis on Ankit Dhall</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ankit-dhall.github.io/portfolio/tags/data-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Canadian Children&#39;s Retail Market</title>
      <link>https://ankit-dhall.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ankit-dhall.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-3/</guid>
      <description>This project analyzes the Canadian census dataset for 2016 published by Statistics Canada and aims to understand the children&amp;rsquo;s retail market in order to help set up new store locations.
This analysis would help businesses understand it&amp;rsquo;s potential consumers, population distribution, purchase powers, and potential opportunities while setting up retail stores or rolling out new products to market.
In general, this particular analysis looks at different components of the Canadian census statistics to answer a few main business objectives:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toronto Bike Share Ridership Analysis</title>
      <link>https://ankit-dhall.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ankit-dhall.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-4/</guid>
      <description>This project analyzes and visualizes trip data of the Toronto Bike Share program in order to understand usage patterns and statitsics. Toronto Bike Share program caters to thousands of riders that make use of the bike rental service set up across multiple stations in and around the city of Toronto.
This analysis would potentially help the business understand it&amp;rsquo;s riders, usage patterns, user types, and potential pain points and use this information for the purposes of demand modelling to optimize costs and increase revenue and help improve customer experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ontario Museum Association Market Research</title>
      <link>https://ankit-dhall.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ankit-dhall.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-1/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this research is to understand the favourability of digital museums amongst people and help the client make changes in accordance with the market demand.
This research would help gauge consumer perception about the digitalization of museums and enable us to find opportunities for further improvement.
Link to Project Results
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TD Mutual Fund Investment Database Design</title>
      <link>https://ankit-dhall.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ankit-dhall.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-2/</guid>
      <description>This project works on designing and building a database solution for the TD Mutual Fund Investment by understanding business requirements for the corresponding form.
This solution would help the business build and maintain an end-to-end database solution to store customer information and mutual fund investments.
Link to GitHub Repository
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
