<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Ankit Dhall</title>
    <link>https://ankit-dhall.github.io/portfolio/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Ankit Dhall</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ankit-dhall.github.io/portfolio/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thermal Demand Modelling</title>
      <link>https://ankit-dhall.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ankit-dhall.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-9/</guid>
      <description>This research aims at applying a novel idea of utilizing an ANN (Artificial Neural Network) black-box model to predict the space heating demand of households in Toronto, Ontario, Canada.
This research was conducted as a continuation of an ongoing study at the Ryerson Centre for Sustainable Energy Systems (CSES).
Being able to model and predict the space heating needs of a household can help reduce energy consumption, and in turn, reduce the total greenhouse gas emissions from households.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time-Series Demand Forecasting</title>
      <link>https://ankit-dhall.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ankit-dhall.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-8/</guid>
      <description>This project aims to implement a time-series forecasting model, aimed at understanding future market demand and DSLAM usage including equipment failure rates.
This analysis would help the business by understanding the growth trend, DSLAM failure rate, and future demand. This information can then be leveraged to reduce overhead costs by setting up the right DSLAM capacity for a region and conducting the required maintenance to increase total capacity.
Link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pinterest Image Tagging</title>
      <link>https://ankit-dhall.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ankit-dhall.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-7/</guid>
      <description>This project aims to implement an image classification model using transfer learning, aimed at providing users on Pinterest with category suggestions for any images they might upload.
This implementation would help users identify and categorize their images more effectively and efficiently, thus improving user experience and engagement on the platform.
The project also implements LIME analysis in order to help explain and understand model predictions.
Link to GitHub Repository
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Organization and Indexing using PySpark</title>
      <link>https://ankit-dhall.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ankit-dhall.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-6/</guid>
      <description>This project aims to implement a search engine using PySpark on Hadoop.
It portrays the use of PySpark to organize and index an entire dataset using TF-IDF and perform a search given a query.
This particular project utilizes Spark RDD&amp;rsquo;s as well as specialized Spark functions that can be leveraged to perform high-performance distributed computing.
Link to GitHub Repository
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toronto Bike Share Ridership Analysis</title>
      <link>https://ankit-dhall.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ankit-dhall.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-4/</guid>
      <description>This project analyzes and visualizes trip data of the Toronto Bike Share program in order to understand usage patterns and statitsics. Toronto Bike Share program caters to thousands of riders that make use of the bike rental service set up across multiple stations in and around the city of Toronto.
This analysis would potentially help the business understand it&amp;rsquo;s riders, usage patterns, user types, and potential pain points and use this information for the purposes of demand modelling to optimize costs and increase revenue and help improve customer experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Similarity Search using Permutation Based Indexing</title>
      <link>https://ankit-dhall.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ankit-dhall.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-5/</guid>
      <description>This project aims to implement a distributed architecture using python to implement similarity search on a given dataset.
Such an implementation can prove extremely useful in a variety of applications including finding similarities between genome sequences and retrieveing relevant information based on a given query.
This particular implementation works on a dataset containing Accident Information in the UK and can help businesses to search for relevant accident records based on a search criteria.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
